#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### **Shashank Sharma**

Contact: +919950995984, +916375617600 E-Mail ID: -shashank.sharma830@gmail.com

Skype ID: -shashank. sharma27

# **Summary**



I have five years plus experienced in the field of remote sensing & GIS and also doing watershed filed survey. Well-versed in quantitative analytical research. Experienced on various Geospatial technology specific projects and multiple various databases. My core expertise are advanced satellite image processing, land cover mapping, time-series analysis, land use and land cover change (LULC) analysis, Feild survey based on DGPS & GPS devices. Map production and Creating vector property maps

# Work Experience

Worked with *G.B. Pant* 'National Institute of Himalayan Environment'(NIHE) as a **Project Coordinator** Post for the Project of "Rejuvenation of Kosi River and People Participation" at Almora, Uttarakhand. (**August-2020 to September-2020**)

Worked with Ajmer Development Authority as a **GIS Expert** Post (**February-2020 to 5-August-2020**)

- 1. Digitized Draft Master Plan (2033) of Ajmer.
- 2. Digitized Existing Land use and Prepare Base Map of Ajmer Zonal Plan.
- 3. Marked Objection Suggestions of ADA, Land use Mark on Google Earth, Digitized Government Land of ADA on GIS Software.

Worked with Renoverse Industry Private Limited, Udaipur as a **GIS Expert** Post for the Project of "GIS Based Study of Alsigarh Watershed, Udaipur" (**From-November 2019 to December 2019**)

- 1. Procured Resourcesat-2 LISS-IV MSS Satellite Imagery from NRSC, Hyderabad of Alsigarh Watershed.
- 2. Georeferencing and Digitization the SOI Toposheet, Cadastral map, Drainage, DEM, Vegetation Indices etc.
- 3. Land use Classification, Soil Moisture Index as per the project requirement

Worked with Rajasthan Geospatial Service's, Jaipur as a **GIS Expert** Post for the Project of "Zonal Development Planning of Nainwa" (**From-April 2019 to August 2019**)

- 1. Collecting and interpreting geographical data for Nainwa Zonal Plan
- 2. Digitizing Land use map of Nainwa, Doing GPS Survey of Nainwa Zonal Area.

Worked with MGNREGA at Jila Parishad, Ajmer as a **GIS Expert Post** for the Project of "Technical Support for Operationalization of Saksham GIS Faculty Centre for Strengthening INRM (Integrated Natural Resource Management) Plan Preparation Supported by Geospatial techniques in Rajasthan under MGNREGA". (**From Mid-August To March 2019**).

- 1. Delineate Groundwater Potential Zones of Rajasthan State.
- 2. Working in NRSC Bhuvan Portal, for using different thematic maps.
- 3. Georeferencing and Digitization the cadastral maps.
- 4. Give GIS Training to all JTS's and JEN's for NRM Planning.
- 5. Effectively communicate between team members regarding logistics, operations etc.

Worked with NABARD Consultancy Service Pvt Ltd, Jaipur as a **GIS Expert and District** Coordinator of MELD Project (February-2015 to August-2018)

- 1. Collecting and interpreting geographical data for Impact Assessment of Watershed Area.
- 2. Done Impact Assessment of Ajmer and Bikaner Division 234 IWMP Watershed Blocks (25% Micro Watershed Area).
- 3. I was purchased 468 LISS-IV MSS Satellite Imagery from NRSC, Hyderabad of Ajmer and Bikaner Division 234 IWMP Watershed Blocks (25% Micro Watershed Area).
- 4. I have leaded the team as a District Coordinator Post and Collecting GPS Coordinates, Monitored Watershed Area.
- 5. Georeferencing and Digitization the Satellite Imagery.
- 6. Conducted analysis and presented data from multiple sources including vector, raster, databases,
  - Updating spatial data and support in research and acquisition of spatial data. Maintained GIS database and created tools, which allows user to access data.
- 7. Creating, maintaining, and updating GIS data and supported in statistical analysis Digitized GIS data and manipulated data to meet user needs.
- 8. Prepare Monthly, Quarterly, Annual, Preparatory Phase, Work Phase Report of IWMP MELD Ajmer District Watershed Area.

## **Educational Qualification**

- M.Sc. Remote sensing & Geoinformatics in 2013 from MDS University, Ajmer
- MA(Geography) in 2009-2011 from MDS University, Ajmer
- BA (Geography, Economics, Political science) in 2006-2009 from MDS University, Ajmer

## **Research Experience**

S. Sharma ;( 2015) "Delineate Groundwater Potential Zones of Ajmer District "International Journal of Remote Sensing and GIS, Volume 4, Issue 2, 2015, 41-40 ISSN 2277–9051

I have done research on Impact Assessment of Integrated Watershed Management Programme (IWMP) Under Mukayamantri Jal Swalamban Yojana and Using Remote Sensing Technique of IWMP-4, Block-Masuda, District, Ajmer,Rajasthan

I am working research paper on Urban Sprawl Mapping of Ajmer City and Its Tentatively Publish in December 2020

### **Trainings Program and Workshops**

- Participated in National Conference on Science Day on 28th to 29th Feb.2012 at MDS University, Ajmer.
- Participated in National Conference on DGPS & Bhuvan on 25<sup>th</sup> March 2013 at MDS University,
- Participated in the Training Program on IGIS Software (Integrated GIS & IP Software) organized by Dept. of Remote Sensing and Geoinformatics & ISRS Ajmer Chapter at MDS University, Ajmer from 23<sup>rd</sup> to 25<sup>th</sup> May,2013.
- Participated In "EDUSAT" Basics course on "Remote Sensing, GIS, GPS" organized by IIRS Dehradun at MDS University, Ajmer 2011.

## **Technical Skills:**

- 1. **GIS Software: ARC** GIS 10.5, Erdas Imagine 2015, ENVIS 4.8, QGIS 3.14, Global Mapper 20.0, Google Earth Pro, etc.
- 2. **IT Skills:** Tally 9.0, C++, Basic Computer Hardware Assembling, Handled Various Types of Computer Software, RSCIT Computer Course from Kota Open University, Kota
- 3. Field Equipment's: Trimble DGPS, Garmin and Trimble Handled GPS

## **Personal Details**

Date of Birth : 29th Sept. 1988

Nationality : Indian

Language : Hindi & English

Marital Status : Married

Address : 231/27, Avadhpuri Jones Ganj, Ajmer, Rajasthan-

305001

## Disclaimer:

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibilities for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars

Date: -02-10-2020

Place: -Ajmer Shashank Sharma